um so I got a question where is the best
place to learn goang um I've answered
this question many times but I'm making
this is a fresh video with the new
information that I have as of you know
2024 whenever the date is on this video
um the answer is pretty
typical uh go to the source read The
Source Luke um go to the major sources
for that and I have put all of those
together and I've been maintaining them
in my own list which is it is a little
bit out of date I should probably go to
it but let's go have a look at my list
of go resources again it's just one list
out there there are lots of lists out
there please make sure you evaluate them
for yourself but let's take a moment to
go look at where we can find this all
right so I just got that for the image
but if you go to um github.com
Rob uh Slash uh awesome
go and this you know the the the
creation of an awesome go list is a
pretty typical thing uh it says here my
personal list of awesome go cod tools
books learning and resources I'm very
picky about what makes it on want to
learn go start here there are other
go um lists out there and I made my own
because some of the ones that out there
are really bad um so I'm going to talk
to you first about the stuff that I
suggest you use and then I'm going to
talk about the stuff that people will
obviously find that and what I think
about it and you can make your own
decision again these are highly
opinionated decisions based on my own
experience and other people you know
experiences may vary so so please don't
take it the wrong way um and not my
Approach is not going to be the same
that a lot of people might might want
they might want to do it in a a more you
know radical way so the first thing is
tour of go so there's a couple things to
know about tour of go um let's let's
actually go there now ah get it there's
G to be so many of those you just can't
avoid it open like a new tab so here we
have tour go the biggest problem with
Touro that you will find if you go
to uh the source code for T ofo is that
it hasn't been maintained nor is it
finished uh and so you kind of get
dropped off um it's a little bit comical
to read about the issues list on tour go
on GitHub and all of the many many
things that they plan to do and didn't
do um even though I still list this as
the First Resource this is the first
place I went to get a feel for go to
play around with it uh but the thing to
know about Toro is that you are going to
hit blockers that I've been dealing with
people from 9 to 19 teaching them coding
and older and they tend to to Bo at the
tutorial section where it goes into
bitwise mathematics for a beginner um
there's a lot of C coders out there and
people like that are going to love it
and it's really clear that the tour of
go was created primarily for people who
are already programmers they've already
programmed to something else and so it's
a good way to get a sense of it it's
still uh the best the best way to to get
going in it um it's also not the First
Resource that I um I mean it's not the
first way to learn how to program right
it's the first way to learn how to learn
go after you kind of already know how to
program something else uh I'm just going
to put a plugin for the beginner boost
we haven't got the videos started yet
but when we we are going to be doing the
polyglot approach to programming and we
will be learning python uh go and python
JavaScript and go at the same time and
the point of that um is to see how the
languages differ and what their goals
are um some people may ask why those
languages those are the the the biggest
languages and they have the biggest um
adoption and they're sort of ubiquitous
they're all targeted at at applying to
lots of things so please stay tuned for
those videos that is why um I can
mention the Toro because when we do the
videos together when we learn and go
together we're not going to use Tor of
go for that no we're going to start much
much simpler than that with very neonic
um easy to use um projects and that
that's just that's how we're going to do
it and it will take us a little bit
longer to learn all three languages just
like it would you know like polyot kids
that grow up with you know I don't know
German and English in the household
tends to their their their language
learning gets delayed a little bit but
then when they when they finally do
learn those two languages they tend to
pick up other languages much faster and
that is the approach that's my I don't
there's no science behind that I just
believe in it deeply uh that poly got
learning poly got coding is the best
approach to programming so that is quite
I should make a whole video about that
but that is the reason the Tor of go is
okay is the first language listed here
okay so the next the next uh resource
here is these by the way these come from
the go community that itself how to
write go code uh this is an absolute
mandatory thing that you must read uh it
talks about using Goan tidy they've kept
this this particular document up to date
um it tells you how to initialize a
project uh it is absolutely fantastic
now it does have a bunch of assumptions
about knowing how to use the command
line and stuff this is why it's so
important that you go through the other
elements of the Boost and particularly
the Linux uh stage and um and you know
the terminal stage so you can learn
about how to use the terminal Linux
terminal uh or a Unix terminal of some
kind so that you can do these things
because the go community and
particularly in the documentation
assumes that you're already uh pretty
good on the command line all right so
the effective go is very important to
understand why things are the way they
are uh when to use what kind of thing um
the term idiom right so coding idioms
the common ways to write code that are
generally accepted um in order to
represent something when multiple ways
of writing it could be you know a
possibility so this is super important
that you get that so far every one of
these resources is Free by the way um
somebody sometime ago recommended go 101
to me and I did review this um this goes
into extreme detail uh you can buy a
copy that's up to you um I have not
looked at the source code of this
particular resource in a very long time
it's been more than 5 years since I read
it um I don't know if they've kept up to
date
with uh the many different things out
there including generics um but again so
this is one of the ways you can kind of
dive in I'm looking for generic
specifically right now there they are us
can use and read use and read composits
okay so we have
generics uh type composite examples nice
okay so it looks like they've added uh
they've added generics um when this was
first recommended to me I was a little
bit nervous about it but it looks like
it is really gotten better um and it
does look like it it covers pretty much
everything uh why do I like it the the
main reason I like it is it's very very
exhaustive perhaps too much so for a
beginner but it also is a sort of
community effort even though they also
sell it um I don't know anything about
them or their or the authors or anything
but it does look pretty damn good um and
so if you want to kind of dig down in uh
you can do that now I do want to pause
here because you know the best way to
learn a thing is to write something
significant in the thing now maybe you
have sort of contrived project when
you're first starting out but eventually
you need to actually make something you
want it can be a twitch integration and
an API or YouTube integration or it can
be you know your own zcas and program
from the command line it can be any
number of things but the point is that
you know don't spend too much time
reading books um you know you should
probably spend a minimal amount of time
reading this material to get your head
arounded and then you should immediately
start thinking about that one project
that you want to make because that is
going to inspire you to keep going it's
going to help you do the research to go
look up what it what it was believe it
whether you like Mark Zucker or not uh
he's quoted in the code.org video as
saying how he learned to code he said it
started out making something fun for my
sisters and me this is this quote from
Mark Zuckerberg's and then I just kept
adding things to it made it a little bit
more tweaked a little bit more kept
learning a little bit more that is the
technique TJ holuk says if you want to
learn something find an existing thing
that you like and rewrite write it and
see if you might even be able to do it
better you're going to learn you have
the answer at the back of the book
because it's already been done so you
can those are methods that you should
probably start to use right away I've
talked about it in a different video but
I want to really point that out here
because if you spend too much time
reading every single thing and the go
one-on-one book not only will you get
tired of it um you know you'll you you
might miss the opportunity to have a
really stick by by actually putting into
practice and I can't speak to how many
of these um explanations actually come
with you know functional projects for
you to to do definitely don't just type
what's in the book into a thing um you
can do that kind of with Touro for a
while but as soon as possible get rid of
that um that's really important if you
don't do that you're going to be sort of
mired um in in the you know the book
learning place so people people
similarly get mired in you know YouTube
land they're just watching YouTube
tutorials and they're not they're going
through the tutorial but they don't
learn anything so you know just be aware
of that and make sure you're you're you
know producing something valuable for
yourself and for others um uh what is
this go using go modules um okay so this
is another um this is super interesting
so go modules uh go modules are arguably
one of the most confusing parts of go
they have one of the most radically
strange histories and I'm actually
fighting with them now because the new
inner Source movement makes everything
and go private which makes it
ridiculously difficult to do something
as simple as importing a package because
now during cicd with a GitHub action
I've done other videos considerable
videos on this uh ultimately I've
decided to use go vendoring which is a
separate topic but if you don't
understand modules you won't be able to
do right modu or software so definitely
include that in your in your
learning um uh the go code review
comments these are uh the from the go
project itself um and looks like it's
moved
but the point of this is that let's see
the go Wiki GitHub has moved to go. okay
um these These
are um very opinionated specific things
that would keep your code commits from
being accepted into the go project
itself and you know while they're not
strictly uh mandated to any for anybody
to use uh getting good with what they
are and understanding them is worth
getting into uh this is the only place
that this is documented so that is not
in a book anywhere this is the place to
go it's also free so so make sure you go
through that um let's see what else we
got um uh code something with
concurrency I I I already told you about
the projects um uh that's super
important that you understand context
and concurrency uh read go code review
comments for style guide oh I think I
already clicked on that just now the go
program link specification okay so you
know when when you talk about read the
manual this is literally the manual and
we're going to talk about this when we
get into uh to the language things we
talk about the different languages and
this is also the reason that I think um
even though I don't think it's a part of
the beginner boost I believe everybody
should learn to read ebnf abnf which is
all the rfc's in the world are written
in them I'll do a separate video on
reading specifications but not being
able to read a specification is a
serious handicap in the technology world
uh and the ability to read ebnf in in
this particular case gives you a lot of
superpower when it comes to
understanding the language um upon side
note fun fact I actually created
pegan uh because I am into this kind of
thing so much so this is
panev um and this is you know this is my
own uh language that and kind of
extended from Peg which I use for
different things um and and I'll I'll
talk about that another day but that
that's because ebnf is is inadequate for
representing certain things but it's
it's become the standard for for
documenting how a language is actually
implemented if you do not follow the
ebnf specification you are not
implementing the language properly so
that's that's if you really want to go
there there's no YouTube videos going to
go tell you to read the ebn on YouTube I
promise you that if you if you find
anybody on the internet telling you to
go read the specification for go in
order to learn go please let me know
because I want to like I don't know find
that person and give him a kiss on the
mouth because I I don't know I find it
annoying a little bit of a rant ear I
find it annoying that people are not
recommended to go to the standard
specifications more frequently they're
shown some dummy's book or somebody's
YouTube video or something they're
always given the you know they're
they're they're given the the the the
you know easy stuff that ends up being
wrong most of the time and at at worst
um I mean at worst being ultimately
wrong and at best being overly watered
down and diluted and not significant
enough even for you to become a serious
software developer you need to go to the
specifications you need to read them you
need to get used to reading them so that
when you need to go look something up
you don't have to go ask somebody about
it you can literally go to the manual
and and so learning go is the next one
uh whoops okay so learning go that's
what I when I mentioned books I I kind
of jumped ahead on the book there uh the
go standard Library so this actually is
a great way to see good go code one of
the best ways to learn go is to read
good go code and there is a lot of great
go code inside of the standard libraries
um including how to write a parser all
kinds of stuff um there are a number of
individual projects uh that I probably
should update this actually there are a
number of individual projects which I
will commit to you right now that I will
add these projects to here so that you
can study a project that has really used
go effectively um and that I'm just
going to name them really quickly before
I add them here so because you know in
addition to the ghost standard Library
if you want to see somebody who's
actually implemented something well and
I mean well um you want to go like
something comes to mind is Argo CD comes
to mind that's actually been run really
well the kind project KD is BU done
really well um and uh there was another
one recently that I was looking at and I
I can't remember it at this moment oh
sorry for the Distortion a little bit of
distortion there um so let me tell you
some projects to stay away from the
kubernetes code base is a disaster uh
Hugo go Hugo absolute disaster one of
the worst code bases I've ever read um
the cube CTL Pro program that everybody
has to use also total disaster um be
Cobra Cobra the thing that everybody
uses to do their command line parsing
the actual source code for Cobra is
ridiculously bad it was done really
quickly kind of like Minecraft and and
it was and it's still remains popular
these projects that you might think oh
I'm sure these are going to be the
standards they're absolutely horrible um
so you know stick with the those other
ones if you have a question about a
project and you want me to evaluate a
project front please come join me for
coffee boost in the morning ask me what
do you think of this project and I'll
try to do a quick little vetting of the
project to see there's some pretty big
glaring signs when when a project is bad
Helm oh my God it's just so bad it
doesn't matter how popular it is and how
many people use it this code base is
horrible um so anyway go stick with the
go standard library because it's had to
been approved by the go team themselves
who are very very you know pedantic
about everything um there are you know
exceptions to that statement but that's
mostly true and and then um as I said
you know kind and um and Argo CD Argo CD
is done really well too so I mean there
probably some other ones I just can't
remember them right now watch the the
awesome page and I'll add those back um
when it at that point it's probably time
for you to dive in to Lear and go and uh
true um John has a a a tremendous um uh
writing style he's got a really great
writing style um learning go is supposed
to be for a beginner
uh thing for learning go but he says
really quickly in there that it's
actually not that it the best thing
about learning go is it answers a bunch
of the questions about the idioms that
are not talked about it's like when
should you use an interface versus uh
when should you return it I mean once
you use an interface once you use a
structure right um so these are this is
a justification of some of the most
common idioms that are out there um and
it's it's more about the craft of wri
and go even though it says learn and go
which as if you know riy when somebody
says learning go that's the book That's
supposed to take you from Zero to Hero
right it doesn't it learning go assumes
you know uh a certain amount of go
already and he say he says so in The
First beginning of the book which I
think is is somewhat unfortunate um
because it is a it is a great resource
other than that and um yeah this one of
the ones you'd have to pay for um there
there's another there's a listing for
Bonsai here which is old please
disregard that for now uh I'll be
immediately removing that um uh Bonsai
command tree is Bonsai is a program that
I wrote to replace Cobra um I do think
that you everybody should learn how to
write a cobra project even though I
despise the Cobra project uh it is grown
a lot I I want to say that some of the
stuff I did with Bonsai has maybe helped
the project move in the right direction
um and I'll make a separate video about
that but just um when we do go when we
do go for Enterprise development which
we are going to do in skill stack um so
let me just put you pull this up for for
now so we will be learning um even
though we're going to be learning uh
right here and it says um where is
it um getting learn Linux machine there
it is learn a code so learn a code is
Javascript is we're going to learn to
code in JavaScript uh go in Python but
then another part of the Boost we're
going to actually develop enterprise
software and go and for this particular
part right here we're going to be doing
uh we're going to write an API and we're
going to write um a a a client an API
client uh probably the twitch some sort
of twitch inter ation or something and
then we're also going to oh look at that
we got we got the bubbles because I did
the P sign and I mean the balloons and
then we're going to do um uh we're
probably we're going to do at least one
command from the command line using
Cobra um and we will talk about cobra
versus you know five CLI or um or mine
or by bonai thing um it isn't it is
essential that you learn how to use
Cobra to make a command line to utility
in 2024 whether or not I like it doesn't
matter that is by far the industry
standard for that kind of thing so
knowing how to do that knowing how to
make uh an Enterprise API um how to
deliver Enterprise API and in uh and go
a rest API using the tools that are out
there and I I don't want to start
listenting them here because you know
using open API and all the the things
using the net HTP library for doing it
as well as why you might want to reach
for a framework like jyn which is unsexy
but still by far the leader U out there
in deployment land um sometimes the most
effective framework uh or library is not
necessarily the newest one in fact very
frequently that's true you want maturity
in the Enterprise more than you want
Cutting Edge uh there was a famously a
guy on on who shared an unpopular
opinion on the go on the go Time Podcast
and he said his unpopular opinion is he
will not allow any techn techology in
his architected environment that's less
than 7 years old and I think that's
pretty extreme I mean there are so many
things you would not be able to adopt in
that case um but and you know so but the
point is is a lot of times you want
stuff that's old so as you're going
through and you're doing the education
and and go um make sure you consider
those resources uh I'll be keeping my
awesome go thing here updated I did put
a bunch of my own stuff here that's
mostly experimental uh my bonsai stuff
um this stuff is fun but uh bar is my
own use use of of generics uh my own
configuration manager for that some web
request stuff um I've link I've linked
to most of my stuff here but I haven't
been maintaining this completely all the
time but if you want to see some of the
examples that I've tried to make to do
different things this is where I kind of
maintain the list of them uh many of
them have been superseded by by new
changes to the language most most
specifically um the use of um the the
generics library has has superseded some
of the stuff that I used to do with
slices but if you want to see how to
implement some of the data structures
and algorithms that are out there
already um and you want to just get a
sense of how I've done them you can go
look at um uh where is it bars and no
not bars where is it there's I think
it's types I'm trying to find it here uh
but this is just my experimentation
there's other people that have other
code you can find um oh Str is it Str
yeah this is my data structures
algorithm um and I do have uh a scanner
I wrote um U you know uh I wrote a
scanner to go through and parse content
if you want to see that I my own yq
utility using the stuff I learned from
kind um so that's some of the stuff that
you can go to for me there's these are
some actually some really awesome
libraries in here I would not have
listed otherwise low Dash is completely
uh irrelevant now with generics so that
needs to
removed um let's see only say to write a
Google file uh to write to a file this
is super important that you read this
this is because this is atomic file
rights with locked
file uh Proto buff stuff so it does look
like I need to go clean this up the
question was asked today so I'm going
ahead I'm answering it today but I'm
probably not going to clean this
particular page up until we're getting
ready to start doing our coding and go
and we're probably several months away
from that so if you but but if you want
to follow if you want to follow the
awesome go list and for those changes
there you go H okay that's my last pun
for the day and that's the end of this
video because you know the rest of it
you can figure out on your own uh this
is rwx Rob coming you from the subu
thank you for checking it out we'll see
you in morning Boo come on and say hi
thanks